Finding Aid for the Ferdinand Praeger Collection of Scores, circa 1829-1891
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Keyboard works, 1837-1891, I.; Item 001-369
  - Piano, 1837-1891, A.; Item 001-332
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 English opera themes / [18--], [1] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 2, Item 081)
      Contents: English ballad -- Song.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Eventide / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 32 cm. (Box 2, Item 082)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Ex abrupto: souvenir fantastique de Figaro de Mozart, pour piano / [18--], [13] p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Souvenir fantastique de Figaro de Mozart (Box 2, Item 083)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [2], [9-12].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Feuille d'album, piano, F major, (1889) Feuille d'album [in F major], 1889, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 2, Item 084)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink), sections marked with red ink. Caption: 20 Dec. 1889.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Feuille d'album, piano, F major, (1891) Feuille d'album [in F major], 1891, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 2, Item 085)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). "[Stammbuchblatt?] für meinem Freund Max Blume. May 18, 1891. Sind vom Ganzen mir zu Kommen, Sind von dir nun aufgenommen."--Bottom of p. [1].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Finette: galop / [18--], [6] p. of ms. music; 29 cm. (Box 2, Item 086)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [1-6]. P. [6] labeled "Introd."
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 1 Fleeting thoughts no. 1 / 1882, [2] p. of ms. music; 34 cm. (Box 2, Item 087)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption (partially effaced): 30 Nov 1882.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 2 Fleeting thoughts no. 2 / 1883, [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 088)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption (partially effaced): 23/1 1883.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 3 Fleeting thoughts no. 3 / 1883, [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 089)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption (partially effaced): Jan 7 1883.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 4 Fleeting thoughts no. 4 / 1883, [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 090)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 28/1 1883.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 6 Fleeting thoughts no. 6 / 1883, [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 091)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 18/9 1883.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 7 Fleeting thoughts no. 7 / 1883, [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 092)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 21/9 1883.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 8 Fleeting thoughts no. 8 / [1883?], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 093)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 9 Fleeting thoughts no. 9 / [1883?], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 094)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 10 Fleeting thoughts no. 10 / 1883, [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 095)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 29/9 83.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 11 Fleeting thoughts no. 11 / 1883, [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 096)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 1/10 1883.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 12 Fleeting thoughts no. 12: Andante religioso / [ca. 1883], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm.; Alternate title: Andante religioso (Box 2, Item 097)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 13 Fleeting thoughts no. 13 / [ca. 1883], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 2, Item 098)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 14 Fleeting thoughts no. 14 / [ca. 1883], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 099)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 15 Fleeting thoughts no. 15 / [ca. 1883], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 100)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [1].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 16 Fleeting thoughts no. 16 / [ca. 1883], [1] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 101)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 17 Fleeting thoughts no. 17 / [ca. 1883], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 102)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 18 Fleeting thoughts no. 18 / [ca. 1883], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 103)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 19 Fleeting thoughts no. 19 / [ca. 1883], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 104)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 20 Fleeting thoughts no. 20 / [ca. 1883], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 105)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 21 Fleeting thoughts no. 21 / 1884, [2] p. of ms. music; 30 cm. (Box 3, Item 106)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 2/4 84.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 22 Fleeting thoughts no. 22 / 1884, [2] p. of ms. music; 30 cm. (Box 3, Item 107)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 2/4 1884.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 23 Fleeting thoughts no. 23 / 1884, [1] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 3, Item 108)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 4/4 84.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 68 Fleeting thoughts no. 68: Stilles Leid = Silent sorrow / [ca. 1885], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Stilles Lied Alternate title: Silent sorrow (Box 3, Item 109)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 69 Fleeting thoughts no. 69 / [ca 1885], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 110)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on insert pasted on p. [1].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 70 Fleeting thoughts no. 70 / 1885, [3] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 3, Item 111)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 3 July 1885.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 71 Fleeting thoughts no. 71 / [ca. 1885], [1] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 3, Item 112)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 72 Fleeting thoughts no. 72: Nordisches Volkslied / [ca. 1885], [2] p. of ms. music; 30 cm.; Alternate title: Nordisches Volkslied (Box 3, Item 113)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 74 Fleeting thoughts no. 74 / 1883, [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 3, Item 114)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 17/3 1883.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 75 Fleeting thoughts no. 75 / 1882, [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 3, Item 115)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 28 Nov. 1882.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 76 Fleeting thoughts no. 76 / [between 1882 and 1891], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 116)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 86 Fleeting thoughts no. 86 / [between 1882 and 1891], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 117)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 87 Fleeting thoughts no. 87 / [between 1882 and 1891], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 118)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 88 Fleeting thoughts no. 88 / [between 1882 and 1891], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 119)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 89 Fleeting thoughts no. 89 / [between 1882 and 1891], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 120)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 90 Fleeting thoughts no. 90 in E [minor] / [between 1882 and 1891], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 121)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 91 Fleeting thoughts no. 91 in A / [between 1882 and 1891], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 122)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 92 Fleeting thoughts no. 92 / [between 1882 and 1891], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 123)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 93 Fleeting thoughts no. 93 / [between 1882 and 1891], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 124)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 95 Fleeting thoughts no. 95 / [between 1882 and 1891], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 125)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 96 Fleeting thoughts no. 96 (A minor) / [between 1882 and 1891], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 126)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on insert pasted on p. [2].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 97 Fleeting thoughts no. 97 (G [major]) / [18--], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 127)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 98 Fleeting thoughts no. 98 (C minor) / [between 1882 and 1891], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 128)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 99 Fleeting thoughts no. 99 (in F) / [between 1882 and 1891], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 129)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, no. 100 Fleeting thoughts no. 100, E minor / [between 1882 and 1891], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 130)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, A major Fleeting thoughts [in A major], 1891, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 131)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 9 May 1891.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, A minor, (1888 Sept. 11) Fleeting thoughts [in A minor], 1888, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 132)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 11 Sept. 88.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, A minor (1888 Dec. 25) Fleeting thoughts [in A minor], 1888, [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 133)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 17/12 1888; Colophon: 25/12 88.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, A minor (1889 Nov. 9) Fleeting thoughts [in A minor], 1889, [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 134)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 9 Nov. 1889.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, A minor (1891 May 31) Fleeting thoughts [in A minor], 1891, [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 135)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 31 May 91.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, A minor (1891 Jun. 5) Fleeting thoughts [in A minor], 1891, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 136)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 5 June 91.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, A♭ major (1888 Dec. 26) Fleeting thoughts [in A flat major], 1888, [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 137)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 26.12.88.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, A♭ major (1891 May 12) Fleeting thoughts [in A flat major], 1891, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 138)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 11 May 91; Colophon: 12 May.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, B♭ major (1891 May 28) Fleeting thoughts [in B flat major], 1891, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 139)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 26 May 1891; Colophon: 28/5.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, C major Fleeting thoughts [in] C maj / [between 1882 and 1891], [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 140)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on insert pasted on p. [4].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, C major (1888 Sept. 12) Fleeting thought [in C major], 1888, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 141)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 12 Sept. 1888.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, C major (1890 Nov. 17) Fleeting thoughts [in C major], 1890, [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 142)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 17/11 90.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, C major (1890 Dec. 18) Fleeting thoughts [in C major], 1890, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 143)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 18/12 90.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, C major (1891) Fleeting thoughts no. [blank in C major], 1891, 3 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 144)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. 1, 3.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, C major (1891 Feb. 18) Fleeting thoughts [in C major], 1891, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 145)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 17/2 91; Colophon: 18/2 91.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, C major (1891 Feb. 22) Fleeting thoughts [in C major], 1891, 3 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 146)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 22 Feb 1891.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, C major (1891 May 6) Fleeting thoughts [in C major], 1891, 3 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 147)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 4 May 1891; Colophon: 6.5.91.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, C minor Fleeting thoughts [in] C min., 1890, 4 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 148)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, D minor Fleeting thoughts [in D minor], 1891, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 149)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 6/3 91.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, E major (1889 Mar.) Fleeting thoughts in E maj., 1889, [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 150)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Cover: March 1889.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, E major (1891 May 23) Fleeting thoughts [in E major], 1891, [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 151)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 23 May 1891.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, E♭ major (1888 Dec. 25) Fleeting thoughts [in E flat major], 1888, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 152)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 22/12 88; Colophon: 25/12 88.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, E♭ major (1891 Feb. 11) Fleeting thoughts [in E flat major], 1891, [1] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 153)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 11 Feb. 91.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, E♭ major (1891 Feb. 15) Fleeting thoughts [in E flat major], 1891, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 154)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: Feb. 15th 91.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, E♭ major, (1891 Mar. 4) Fleeting thoughts [in E flat major], 1891, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 155)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 4/3 91.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, F major, (1891 Jan. 12) Fleeting thoughts [in F major], 1891, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 156)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 6/1 91; Colophon: 12/1 90 [i.e. 91].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, F major (1891 June 6) Fleeting thoughts [in F major], 1891, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 157)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 6 June 91.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, G major (1889 Nov. 16) Fleeting thought in G [major], 1889, 3 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 158)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: Nov. 16 89. Correction on insert pasted on p. 1.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, G major (1891 Mar. 1) Fleeting thoughts [in G major], 1891, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 159)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 1/3 91.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, G minor Fleeting thoughts, G minor, 1888, 2 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 160)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 19 Aug. 88; p. 2 margin: 21 Aug.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Fleeting thoughts, G♭ major Fleeting thoughts [in G flat major], 1891, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 161)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 28 May 1891.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Freudenwalzer / [18--], [5] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 162)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Galops, piano, C major Galop [in C major] / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 3, Item 163)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Galops, piano, C major (1885) Galop [in C major] 1885, [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 3, Item 164)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 24 June 1885.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Galops, piano, G major Galop [in G major] / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 3, Item 165)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Galop brillant / [18--], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 166)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Gavottes, piano, no. 2, G minor Gavotte no. 2 / [18--], [3] p. of ms. music; 28 cm. (Box 3, Item 167)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Gavottes, piano, no. 5, C major Gavotte no. 5 / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 28 cm. (Box 3, Item 168)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Gavottes, piano, no. 5, C major Gavotte no. 5 / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 28 cm. (Box 3, Item 169)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Initial tempo-expression marking: con gravita.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Gavottes, piano, no. 6, A major Gavotte no. 6 / [18--], [3] p. of ms. music; 28 cm. (Box 3, Item 170)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink, some of which is blue). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [1-2].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Gavottes, piano, no. 12, E♭ major Gavotte no. 12 / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 171)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Gavottes, piano, C minor Gavotte [in C minor] / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 36 cm. (Box 3, Item 172)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Severely damaged.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Gavottes, piano, E♭ major Gavotte [in E flat major] / [18--], [3] p. of ms. music; 28 cm. (Box 3, Item 173)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Gavotte de Louis XV / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 174)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Gigue, piano, F minor Giga pour piano / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 32 cm. (Box 3, Item 175)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 La gioja / [18--], [6] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 176)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. 1-6
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Gondoliera, A♭ major Gondoliera / [18--], [3] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 4, Item 177)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Grande valse, piano, E♭ major (Allegro moderato) Grande valse: pour piano [in E flat major, Allegro moderato] / [18--], [7] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 178)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout. Initial tempo marking: Allegro moderato.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Grande valse, piano, E♭ major (Con vivacità) Grande valse: pour piano [in E flat major, Con vivacità] / [18--], [6] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 179)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout. Pencil marking on cover: E?. Initial tempo-expression marking: Con vivacità.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 La grotesque / [18--], [5] p. of ms. music; 25 x 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 180)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Heavily marked with corrections in ink and pencil.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Idylle, piano, G major Idylle [in G major] / 1852, [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 181)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 7 October 52" in caption.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Idylle, piano, A major Idylle [in A major] / 1890, [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 182)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 5/5 90.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Impromptus, piano, A♭ major Impromptu [in A flat major]: composed and dedicated to his friend Dr. Charles Vincent / 1889, 4 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 183)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 28 Sept. 89. Corrections on insert pasted on p. 1.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Impromptus, piano, B♭ major Impromptu [in B flat major] / 1889, [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 184)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: June 1889. "Composed for & dedicated to Miss Smythe"--Caption.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Impromptus, piano, C major Impromptu [in C major] / [18--], [4] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 4, Item 185)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Impromptus, piano, F major Impromptu [in F major] / 1888, [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 186)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 8 June 88.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Impromptu scherzando: piano / [18--], 4 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 187)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Jagdchor = Hunting song / [18--], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Hunting song (Box 4, Item 188)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Jagdlied = hunting song / [18--], 3 p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Hunting song (Box 4, Item 189)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Jubilee gavotte, piano Jubilee gavotte / 1887, [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 4, Item 190)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Severely damaged, some sections unreadable. Probably composed in honor of the 50th anniversary celebration of Queen Victoria's reign.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Jubilee march, piano Jubilee march / 1887, [3] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 4, Item 191)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 The jubilee trumpet waltz = Trompeten Walzer / 1887, [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm.; Alternate title: Trompeten Walzer (Box 4, Item 192)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 1887. Probably composed in honor of the 50th anniversary celebration of Queen Victoria's reign.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Lament, piano Lament; Romance no. 17 / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 193)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Launiger Augenblick: scherzo / [18--], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 194)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Correction on insert pasted on p. [3].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Legende, piano, A minor Legende / 1881, 5 p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 4, Item 195)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 3 August 1881. Corrections on inserts pasted on p. 3, 4.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Lento, piano, G major Lento / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 4, Item 196)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Lento con affetto / 1889, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 197)
      For piano. Title from initial tempo-expression marking. Manuscript (Ink). "Composed for & dedicated to Miss Edith Blyth"--Caption. Caption: August 26th 1889.